const emptyQuestion = {
  question:
    "",
  choices: [
    ""
  ],
  correct: 0
}

const questions =
[
  {
    question: "Who is the author of <em>A Tale of Two Cities</em>?",
    choices: [
      "Charles Dickens",
      "Jane Austen",
      "Daniel Defoe",
      "Arthur Conan Doyle"
    ],
    correct: 0
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the narrator of F. Scott Fitzgerald's <em>The Great Gatsby</em>?",
    choices: [
      "F. Scott Fitzgerald",
      "Nick Carraway",
      "Jay Gatsby",
      "T.J. Eckleburg"
    ],
    correct: 1
  },
  {
    question: "What is Hamlet's mother's name?",
    choices: ["Penelope", "Gertrude", "Ophelia", "Calliope"],
    correct: 1
  },
  {
    question:
      "Identify the source of these lines: 'Beauty is truth, truth beauty, that is all / Ye know on earth, and all ye need to know.'",
    choices: [
      "John Keats's 'Ode To a Grecian Urn'",
      "Shakespeare's <em>The Tempest</em>",
      "Edgar Allan Poe's 'Ligeia'",
      "Sir Philip Sidney's 'Sonnet 64'"
    ],
    correct: 0
  },
  {
    question:
      "When was the oldest surviving copy of Homer's <em>Iliad</em> composed?",
    choices: [
      "From the ninth to the fifteenth century CE",
      "117 BCE",
      "Eight century BCE",
      "Ninth century BCE"
    ],
    correct: 2
  },{
    question:
      "How many novels did Tobias Smollett write?",
    choices: [
      "1",
      "6",
      "16",
      "61"
    ],
    correct: 1
  },
    {
    question:
      "Who is the author of the following lines:<br>'And we are here as on a darkling plain<br>Swept with confused alarms of struggle and flight,<br>Where ignorant armies clash by night?'",
    choices: [
      "Seamus Heaney",
      "Anne Sexton",
      "Lord Alfred Tennyson",
      "Matthew Arnold"
    ],
    correct: 3
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following best describes blank verse?",
    choices: [
      "Unrhymed iambic pentameter",
      "Rhymed iambic tetrameter",
      "Free verse",
      "Accented verse"
    ],
    correct: 0
  },
  {
    question:
      "How old was Miguel Cervantes when he completed <em>Don Quixote</em>?",
    choices: [
      "27",
      "37",
      "42",
      "68"
    ],
    correct: 3
  },
  {
    question:
      "Theocritus is known for his contribution to which major ancient genre?",
    choices: [
      "Pastoral",
      "Epic",
      "Tragedy",
      "Biography"
    ],
    correct: 0
  },
    {
    question:
      "Who first used the phrase, 'To err is human, to forgive divine?'",
    choices: [
      "William Shakespeare",
      "Alexander Pope",
      "William Wordsworth",
      "Emily Dickinson"
    ],
    correct: 1
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of these poems is the shortest (in lines)?",
    choices: [
      "Ezra Pound, 'In a Station of the Metro",
      "William Carlos Williams, 'The Red Wheelbarrow'",
      "Basho, 'An old silent pond'",
      "Marianne Moore, 'Silence'"
    ],
    correct: 0
  },
  {
    question:
      "Lyn Hejinian is known for her contribution to which major twentieth century movement?",
    choices: [
      "Postmodernism",
      "New Formalism",
      "Language Poetry",
      "Martian Poetry"
    ],
    correct: 2
  },{
  question :
    "When the first edition of this poet's works appeared in 1855, the <em> Boston Intelligencer</em> said in its review: 'The author should be kicked out from all decent society as below the level of the brute. He must be some escaped lunatic raving in pitable delerium.' Who was it?",
    choices: [
      "Edgar Allan Poe",
      "Walt Whitman",
      "Ralph Waldo Emerson",
      "John Clare"
    ],
    correct: 1
  },
  {
    question:
      "When this Irish playwright was stopped by U.S. customs in New York, he proclaimed, 'I have nothing to declare except my genius.",
    choices: [
      "Samuel Beckett",
      "George Bernard Shaw",
      "Brian Friel",
      "Oscar Wilde"
    ],
    correct: 3
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the real name of the author of <em>Middlemarch</em>?",
    choices: [
      "Mary Ann Evans",
      "George Eliot",
      "Harriet Carker",
      "Susanna O'Byrne"
    ],
    correct: 0
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the lock in Alexander Pope's 'The Rape of the Lock'?",
    choices: [
      "The gate to a woman's chamber",
      "A section of a canal",
      "A length of hair",
      "A pistol"
    ],
    correct: 3
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the main character in H.G. Wells's <em>The Invisible Man</em>?",
    choices: [
      "Griffin",
      "Baron",
      "Solomon",
      "Evans"
    ],
    correct: 0
  },
  {
    question:
      "What does <em>R.U.R.</em> stand for in Karl Capek's play?",
    choices: [
      "Raliegh University Regents",
      "Rossum's Universal Robots",
      "Randomized Unpredictable Rain",
      "Russian Underground Railroad"
    ],
    correct: 1
  },
  {
    question:
      "The following sentence is the first line of which novel: 'It was a bright cold day in April, and the clocks were strinking thirteen.'",
    choices: [
      "Italo Calvino's <em>Cosmicomics</em>",
      "Thomas Pynchon's <em>Gravity's Rainbow</em>",
      "Virginia Woolf's <em>To The Lighthouse</em>",
      "George Orwell's <em>1984</em>"
    ],
    correct: 3
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the longest of William Shakespeare's plays?",
    choices: [
      "<em>The Comedy of Errors</em>",
      "<em>King Lear</em>",
      "<em>Hamlet</em>",
      "<em>Henry VIII</em>"
    ],
    correct: 2
  }
]
